本剧改编自圣经  这些故事曾改变世界
本剧将始终保持《圣经》真谛
《圣经》前情提要
Previously on The Bible.
退后
Back!
玛利亚  很快你将怀孕生子
Mary, you will soon give birth to a son-
天主之子
the Son of God.
有星要出于雅各伯
A star shall come out of Jacob,
有杖要兴于以色列
and a scepter shall rise out of lsrael.
我坚信您的儿子必是应许为王的那一位
I believe your son is the promised king of his people.
他叫什么名字
What is his name?
耶稣
Jesus.
他的名字是耶稣
His name is Jesus.
比我强的一位要来
There is one to come greater than me.
我不过是旷野中的声音   准备道路
I'm just a voice in the wilderness, preparing the way for the-
迎接上主
Lord.
起来行走
Get up and walk.
这个来自加里肋亚的扰乱者 他是个麻烦
This agitator from Galilee- he's trouble.
有人说那个耶稣让一个死人复活了
They say this Jesus has raised a man from the dead.
天主会将他的忿怒降在所有人身上
God will bring his wrath down upon all of us,
谁知道比拉多会做什么
and who knows what Pilate will do?
大人  有个犹太人在圣殿里惹麻烦
Sir, a Jew has been causing trouble in the temple.
你们不能事奉天主而又事奉钱财
You cannot serve God and money.
倘若动乱在明日再次发生
If the disturbances that took place today are repeated tomorrow,
我会立即关闭圣殿
I will shut the tempie immediately.
你们拆毁这座圣殿 三天之内 我要把它重建起来
Destroy this temple, and I will build it again in three days.
他威胁说要摧毁圣殿
He threatens to destroy the temple.
我们得除掉此人  否则罗马人将摧毁一切
We remove this man, or the Romans destroy everything.
-处决？  -没错
- Execute? - Yes.
一个乡下人的性命  换取天主之国的未来
The life of one peasant for the future of God's nation.
你将为此事悔恨终生
You'lI live to regret this.
一周之内就没人记得他是谁了
He'll be forgotten in a week.
我的儿啊
My son!
你们心神固然切愿  但肉体却软弱
The spirit is willing, but the flesh is weak.
父啊  宽赦他们吧
Father! Forgive them,
因为他们不知道他们做的是什么
for they know not what they do.
那时你在哪  你本应是他的磐石
Where were you? You were supposed to be his rock.
我辜负了他  如今也无法请求他的原谅
I failed him. Now I can't ask him to forgive me.
玛利亚
Mary.
我回来了
I am here.
圣经
感谢YYETS字幕组
原始翻译时间轴及制作
天主教长沙青年团体重制
本字幕采用天主教思高译本
仅供福传学习
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
如果你想为天主教的影视字幕出一份福传的力量， 请来Q群180574695【天主的译站】指导交流!
伯多禄  伯多禄
Peter. Peter!
大家听我说  墓穴是开着的
Everyone. The tomb is open.
-他复活了  -什么
- He's alive. - What?
我看见他了
I saw him.
那不可能
That's not possible.
不  我看见了
No. I saw him.
玛利亚  你可能认错了
Mary, maybe it was someone else.
你们觉得我疯了
You think I'm mad.
伯多禄  你自己去看看那墓吧
Peter, see the tomb for yourself.
求你了
Please.
伯多禄
Peter?
现在你相信了吗
Now do you believe me?
但他走了
But he's gone.
走了
Gone?
不
No.
他回来了
He's back.
对  很新鲜的饼
Yes, very fresh. The bread is fresh.
谢谢
Thank you.
杯子  我需要一个杯子和一点酒
A cup. I need a cup and some wine.
怎么了
What happened?
他的身体
His body.
他的血
His blood.
我就是道路
I am the way,
真理
the truth...
和生命
and the life.
不
No.
不  这不是真的
No, this isn't real.
上主
Lord.
多默
Thomas.
不要再疑虑
Stop doubting...
只要相信
and believe.
真的是你
It is you.
你因看见了我
Because you see me,
才相信吗
you believe.
那些没有看见
Blessed are those...
而相信的
who have not seen me...
才是有福的
and yet... have believed.
四十天之后
当圣神降临在你们身上
When the Holy Spirit comes to you,
你们将佩戴上自高天而来的能力
you'll receive power.
圣神的能力
The power of the Holy Spirit...
将伴随你们所有人  不论你们身在何处
can be with you all, wherever you are.
你们往普天下去
Go into the world...
向一切受造物宣传福音
and preach the gospel to all creation.
我将平安留给你们
Peace be with you.
自逾越节 耶稣被钉在十字架上那天
It's 50 days since Passover-
到现在已经有五十天了
the day Jesus was crucified.
如今成千上万的犹太朝圣者来到耶路撒冷
Now thousands of Jewish pilgrims come to Jerusalem...
庆祝五旬节
for the festival of Pentecost.
（即后来的圣神降临节，为纪念耶稣复活后差遣圣神降临而举行的庆祝节日）
耶稣的追随者们有没有出现
Any sign of Jesus' followers?
没有
No.
我认为他们都已经回到加里肋亚了
I assume they've all gone back to Galilee.
是吗
Do you?
让你的人做好准备
Just make sure your men are ready.
如果他们回来了  你要对付他们
If they return, you have to deal with them.
我不想再一次引起罗马的注意
I cannot call upon the Romans again.
他在那儿
There he is.
斯德望
Stephen.
你在这里我们很高兴  兄弟
We're glad you're here, brother.
往这边走
This way.
我们必须小心  他们在监视我们
We must be careful though. They're watching us.
若望  看到你们都安全我真高兴
John, I'm glad you're all safe.
又见到你很高兴  斯德望
It's good to see you again, Stephen.
玛窦
Matthew.
它会以什么形式出现
What form will it take?
它什么时候来
When will it come?
耶稣说过我们当做的只是祈求
Jesus said all we had to do is ask.
我一直在祈求  每天都在祈求
I have been asking. Every day.
时机到了圣神就会降临
The Holy Spirit will come when the time is right.
我觉得我们应该共同祈祷
I think we should pray together.
我们在天上的父
Our Father, who is in heaven,
愿你的名受显扬
hallowed be your name.
愿你的旨意奉行在人间
Your kingdom come, your will be done,
如同在天上
on earth as it is in heaven.
求你今天赏给我们  日用的食粮
Give us this day our daily bread,
求你宽恕我们的罪过
and forgive us our trespasses,
如同我们宽恕别人一样
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
不要让我们陷于诱惑
And lead us not into temptation-
但救我们免于凶恶
but deliver us from evil.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
看那风  看那云
The wind! The clouds!
耶稣是默西亚
先知曾预言过
他被钉上十字架  但是死而复生
耶稣是默西亚
我见到他被钉上十字架
然后死而复生
颂赞归于上主
他被钉上十字架然后死而复生
犹太同胞们
以及所有居住在耶路撒冷的人们
耶稣是默西亚
在天上我要显出奇事  在地下我要显出神迹
我们是如何会说这些语言的
How can we speak those languages?
是圣神  他与我们同在
The Holy Spirit. He is with us.
感谢你  感谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
弟兄们  来听听这些话
My brothers, come hear the word.
谢谢你  姐妹  谢谢
Thank you, sister. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
玛利亚
Mary?
当圣神降临在你们身上
When the Holy Spirit comes to you,
你们将佩戴上自高天而来的能力
you'll receive power.
金银我都没有
I don't have silver or gold.
只把我所有的给你
But what I have I will give you.
奉纳匝肋人耶稣基督的名
In the name of Jesus Christ,
我们的主和救主
our Lord and Savior,
叫你起来
rise up...
行走
and walk.
快来看看
Come and see this.
太神奇了
It's amazing.
你们觉得我们凭自己的能力使他痊愈了吗
Do you think he is healed by our power?
这能力是出于耶稣  他没有死
It is through Jesus. He did not die.
他仍与我们同在
He is still with us.
是他的能力使这人行走
It is his power that made this man walk.
这事出于耶稣
Jesus did this.
Jesus did this!
这事出于耶稣  这事出于耶稣
Jesus did this! Jesus did this!
这事出于耶稣
Jesus did this!
耶稣
Jesus!
这事出于耶稣
Jesus did this!
耶稣
Jesus!
这事出于耶稣
Jesus did this!
这事出于耶稣  耶稣
Jesus did this. Jesus!
是耶稣  是耶稣
Jesus did this! Jesus did this!
他们在说什么
What are they saying?
他们又在喊那个低贱之人的名字了
They're shouting that wretched man's name again.
他们说他治好了那个乞丐
They say he cured the beggar.
把他们的头目给我抓来
Bring the ringleaders to me.
还有那个说谎的乞丐
And that lying beggar.
这边
This way.
那边  坐下
There. Sit down.
趴下  别动
Get down. Don't move.
他们今天又蛊惑了多少人
How many have they turned today?
估计有五千人
We think 5,000.
五千人
5,000.
告诉我
Tell me,
你们怎么能够
why did you think it would be acceptable
以一个已死的异教徒之名布道
to preach in the name of a dead heretic?
耶稣没有死
Jesus isn't dead.
他还活着
He lives.
他被处决  已经死了
He was executed. He is dead.
这人今天能行走完全是出于耶稣基督的能力
This man walks today only through the power of Jesus Christ.
真的吗
Really?
他生来就是跛子
He has been lame since birth.
明白了
Yes. I see.
从现在开始  你们不许
You are not allowed to speak of this beggar...
再提起这个乞丐
or your dead Messiah...
和你们已死的默西亚
from this moment on.
但这是真理
It is the truth.
-我们有责任将它传扬  -责任？
- We have a duty to speak it. - Duty?
责任
Duty?
我有责任
I have a duty...
对我们的圣殿  对我们的国家
to our temple, to our nation,
对我们的天主
to our God!
我还掌控着法律
I also have the law.
我有权柄
I have the power,
现在你们也在我这儿
and I have you here.
你们必须沉默
You will be silent,
否则我会让你们沉默
or you will be silenced.
把他们带走
Take them away.
起来  快走
Right, come on!
我们不怕死
We are not afraid of death.
奉耶稣基督之名受洗
Be baptized in the name of Jesus Christ.
为得罪之赦 你们都可以受洗
You can all be baptized for the forgiveness of your sins.
他被钉十字架  但他从死中复活
He was crucified, but he rose from the dead!
不可能的  不要听信他
Impossibie! Don't listen to him.
你为何要拒绝耶稣
Why do you resist Jesus?
他是你的救主
He is your Savior.
这是走向永生的道路
The way to everlasting life!
耶稣死了
Jesus is dead!
而你将重蹈他的覆辙
And you'll go the same way.
-亵渎者  -不
- Blasphemer! - No!
耶稣还活着
Jesus is alive.
他们试图杀了他  但失败了
They tried to kill him, but they failed.
他是一位真正的先知
He is a true prophet.
是我们的默西亚
Our Messiah!
你对先知了解多少
What do you know about the prophets?
你们的先知将自己凌驾于法律之上
Your prophet put himself above the law.
这个孩子什么都不知道
This boy knows nothing.
我读过经文
I know the Scriptures!
是吗
Really?
那你应该知道《申命记》
Then you'll know Deuteronomy.
因为他试图
Because he sought...
引诱你们离开上主  你们的天主
to entice you away from the Lord. Your God,
"你们应当首先反对他
"Your hand shall be the first against him,
向他扔石头
and you shall stone him with stones...
直到打死他"
until he dies!"
我看见天开了
I see the heavens opening.
人子站在天主的右边
And the Son of man standing at the right hand of God.
-塔尔索的扫禄  -在  大司祭
- Paul of Tarsus. - Yes, High Priest.
今天的事件可能会引发暴动
That incident today could have started a riot.
他是个异教徒
He was a heretic.
他试图引诱我们的子民远离天主
He was trying to lead our people away from God.
罪有应得
He got what he deserved.
这是民心所向
It was the will of the people.
真的吗
Was it really?
或许
Perhaps...
你和我
you and I...
可以一同为众人了却心愿
might serve the people's will together.
我可以为你驱除这个渣滓
I could flush this scum out for you,
但我需要帮助
but I need help.
你需要什么帮助
What do you need?
人手
Men.
金钱
Money.
和你写的介绍信
Letters of introduction from you.
玛耳曷
Malchus.
我的手下随你调配
My servant is at your disposal.
我们吃吧
Let us eat.
我们幸运地得到
We are blessed to receive-
兄弟姐妹们
Brothers and sisters.
我们的主耶稣
Our Lord Jesus,
被出卖的那一夜
on the night of his betrayal,
拿起饼来
took bread.
感谢了  分开
And when he'd given thanks, he broke the bread.
欢迎你  朋友
Welcome. Friend.
请坐吧
Please.
坐下来和我们一起吃
Sit with us and eat.
相信我
Trust me,
我并不是你们的朋友
I am not your friend.
抓住他们
Take them.
走  走  走  快
Go, go, go. Quickly.
快  快跑
Go on, run away!
这边
This way!
告诉你所有的朋友们
Tell all your friends,
所有耶稣的追随者
all you followers of Jesus,
我  塔尔索的扫禄  会找到你们的
that I, Paul of Tarsus, will find you!
天主
God...
与我同在
is on my side!
他们去哪了
Where did they go?
忽然间就没人宣扬耶稣了
Suddenly no one's talking about Jesus.
我不相信他们会轻易背弃于他
I don't beileve they've just given up on him.
那
So...
他们去哪了
where are they?
我不知道  我发誓
I don't know. I swear.
大马士革
Damascus.
有人提过要去大马士革
Someone said Damascus.
真不知道他们为什么要躲着我
I don't know why they run from me.
我使他们免于天主的审判  他们本应感恩戴德
They should be grateful I'm saving them from God's judgment.
-他们还会敬畏天主吗  -根本不会
- Do they even care about God? - No.
他们离弃天主于不顾
They abandoned God to follow
反而追随这肮脏无知的渣滓
this dirty, uneducated scum.
继续前进
Go on, hah!
你是谁
Who are you?
告诉我你是谁
Tell me who you are!
我就是你所迫害的耶稣
I am Jesus, whom you persecute.
不可能
No!
耶稣已死
Jesus is dead.
不  不
No! No!
我的眼睛  我看不见了
My eyes. I'm blind.
上主
Lord?
阿纳尼雅
Ananias.
往那条叫"直街"的地方去
Go to the street called Straight.
找一个塔尔索人  名叫扫禄
Ask for a man they call... Paul of Tarsus.
扫禄
Paul?
但他与我们为敌
But he beats us.
他四处搜捕你的追随者
He arrests your followers everywhere.
他是我拣选的器皿  要在外邦人
I have chosen him to proclaim my name to the world-
和君王
to the gentiles,
并以色列人面前
their kings...
宣扬我的名
and the sons of lsrael.
只管去吧
Go.
谁在那
Who's there?
你是谁
Who are you?
说话
Speak.
我是你要迫害的人之一
I am one of those you want to destroy.
宽恕我
Forgive me.
我得罪了你们
I've wronged you.
我亵渎了天主
I've wronged God.
我的灵魂已饱受煎熬
My soul is on fire.
请帮助我
Help me.
他是我拣选的器皿  宣扬我的名
I have chosen him to proclaim my name to the world.
主打发我来
I am sent by God.
叫你能看见
For you.
我认得你
I know you.
你去过我家
You came to my house.
不
No.
不  请别抛下我
No. No. Don't leave me.
No. Don't leave me.
我 阿纳尼雅
I, Ananias,
奉基督耶稣之名  为你  扫禄  施洗
baptize you, Paul, in the name of Jesus Christ,
因你是他拣选的器皿  奉他的名改变世界
for he has chosen you to change the world in his name.
奉基督耶稣之名
In the name of Jesus Christ.
耶路撒冷
据说塔尔索的扫禄的眼盲已经痊愈
They say that Paul of Tarsus has recovered from his blindness...
还成为了耶稣门徒
and joined the Galileans.
我替您抓他回来
I'll find him for you.
然后呢
And then?
我再遣人抓你回来吗
Will I have to send someone after you?
不必了
No.
放他们去吧
Let them go.
如加玛里耳所言  人之所为
As Gamaliel said, if this is man's work,
必将溃败
it will not succeed.
天主之旨
If it is God's,
无以抗拒
we cannot fight it.
扫禄的信仰改变了
Paul may have converted,
但世上仍有许多迫切想要铲除耶稣追随者的人
but there are still many keen to stamp out Jesus' followers.
把他带出来
Bring him out.
若望的兄长  门徒雅各伯
The disciple James, brother of John,
被当权者逮捕
has been captured by the authorities.
若望
John.
退后
Keep back.
不
No!
-冷静  -把尸体处理掉
- Come on. - Get rid of him.
若望
John.
听我说  我们必须离开耶路撒冷
Come on. We must leave Jerusalem.
耶稣把我们带来这里
Jesus brought us here.
为我们...他死在这里
He died here... for us.
太危险了
It is too dangerous.
要是我们留在这儿  都活不了
If we stay, we will all die.
我不畏惧死亡
I'm not afraid of death.
我们都不畏惧
None of us are.
但是多默说得对
But Thomas is right.
要是我们死了  就无法为耶稣传道
We can't speak of Jesus if we're dead.
一路平安  朋友们
Travel safely, my friends.
若望  我知道与所爱之人分别的痛苦
John, I know it is hard to part from the people you love,
但你并不是孤身一人
but you are not alone.
永远也不会
You never will be.
很多事变了
Much has changed.
-你准备去哪儿  -可能去北边吧
- Where will you go? - North probably.
去厄弗所
To Ephesus.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我们定会再见的  伯多禄
We will meet again, Peter.
不论在人间  或是在天上
On earth or in heaven.
门徒们被迫离开耶路撒冷
Driven from Jerusalem,
渐渐地成为了传教士
the disciples become missionaries-
也就是宗徒
apostles-
将新信仰的种子传遍五湖四海
spreading the seeds of a new faith far and wide.
保禄行的路最远
No one goes further than Paul.
他跨越地中海 在那里让几百人转变了信仰
He converts hundreds across the Mediterranean.
谢谢
Thank you.
不过他对自己曾迫害过他人的行径一直无法释怀
But his previous life as a persecutor haunts him.
我是塔尔索的保禄
Paul of Tarsus.
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.
就是他
That's him.
我没恶意
I mean you no harm.
大马士革有我的朋友
I have friends in Damascus.
你拜访过他们
You paid them a visit.
你带给他们很大的伤害
You meant them plenty of harm.
我改过自新了
I've changed.
我曾经失明了  但现在又能看得真切了
I was blind. Now I can see.
骗子
Liar.
我以前那么做是因为我确信自己是正确的
I did what I did because I was certain I was right.
确信自己了解天主的...旨意
That I knew what God... wanted.
就像你们现在如此确信一般
As you are certain now.
然后耶稣来找我
But then Jesus came to me.
不是出于义愤或是裁决
Not in righteous anger or in judgment,
而是...
but...
出于爱
in love.
若没有爱  我们便算不得什么
And without love, we are nothing.
（取自《圣经》格林多前书13章）
爱是 含忍的
Love is-is patient.
爱是慈祥的
Love is kind.
爱不嫉妒  不自夸
It is not jealous. It does not boast.
不自大
It is not proud.
不以不义为乐
It keeps no records of wrongs. It-It-
却与真理同乐
It rejoices with the truth.
凡事包容
It bears all things.
凡事相信
It believes all things.
凡事盼望
It hopes all things.
凡事忍耐
It endures all things.
现在存在的
When everything else disappears,
有信  望  爱这三样
faith, hope and love remain.
其中最大的...
But the greatest of these...
是爱
is love.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
路加
Luke.
跟从我  路加
Come with me, Luke.
我无法独自做这些
I can't do this alone.
伯多禄
Peter.
你做了如此多
You have done so much.
我为你而骄傲 渔人的渔夫
I am proud of you, my fisher of men.
我的主
My Lord.
我做了你告诉我要做的
I've done what you told me.
我们在整个犹太传你的福音
We preach your word throughout Judaea.
这只是个开始
That is just the beginning.
世上还有很多人...
There are many across the world...
想要听这道理
who will want to hear you.
如果没有你...
Without you,
那只是...
it's just-
以罗马的名义  开门
Open up in the name of Rome.
回应吧
Answer it.
记住
Remember.
大门向所有人敞开
The door is open to everyone.
你必须跟我们走
You must come with us.
百夫长科尔乃略想要见你
Centurion Cornelius wants you.
记住  大门向所有人敞开
Remember. The door is open to everyone.
一位天使向我显现...
An angel came to me...
让我去找你
and told me to find you,
聆听你所有要说的话
to listen to all you have to say.
求你  救赎我
Please. Save me.
我只是一个跟你们一样的人
I'm just a man like you.
能救赎你的是耶稣
It's Jesus who can save you.
来
Come.
我...伯多禄
I, Peter,
为你施洗  科尔乃略
baptize you, Cornelius,
以圣父  圣子
in the name of the Father, the Son...
及圣神之名
and the Holy Spirit.
科尔乃略是第一个
Cornelius is the first Roman
以耶稣基督之名受洗的罗马人
to be baptized in the name of Jesus Christ.
-谢谢你  -不用谢
- Thank you. - You are welcome.
跟我来
Come with me.
所有人都跟我来
All of you.
凡信他的人
Everyone who believes in Jesus,
因他的名都要获得罪赦
receive forgiveness in his name.
无一例外
Everyone.
伯多禄
Peter.
来跟从我
Come with me,
我要使你成为渔人的渔夫
and I will make you a fisher of men.
我们要做什么
What are we going to do?
改变世界
Change the world.
二十年后
耶稣门徒们把福音
The disciples take the gospel
传到了世界上各大城市
to the world's great cities-
安提约基雅  格林多  罗马
Antioch, Corinth, Rome-
为受压迫的人们带去希望
bringing hope to the oppressed.
我带来了能够减轻你们痛苦的好消息
I bring good news that will relieve your suffering.
一位伟大导师的消息
News of a great teacher.
耶稣基督
Jesus Christ.
对耶稣敞开心扉
Open your hearts to Jesus,
你们将得永生
and you will have everlasting life.
-过来  -把他带走
- Come here! - Get him out of there!
然而  宣扬一个新国度的到来
But preaching of a new kingdom
让掌权者们感到了威胁
threatens those in power.
你是谁
Who are you?
兄弟姐妹们
Brothers and sisters,
我们在苦难中欢欣
we rejoice in our suffering-
因为我们知道
because we know that suffering...
磨难生忍耐
produces perseverance,
忍耐生老练
perseverance creates character...
老练生望德
and character... hope.
在教会的圣传中  十二宗徒全部
Christian tradition says all the disciples
以身殉道
die for their cause.
伯多禄在罗马被倒钉十字架而死
Peter is crucified in Rome upside down.
玛窦在厄提约丕雅(今埃塞俄比亚)殉道
Matthew is killed in Ethiopia,
多默在印度南部受难
Thomas in southern India...
若望在罗马被人下毒
and John is poisoned in Rome.
保禄
Paul.
有人来抓你了
They're coming for you.
拿好了  总得有东西要留传下去
Take these. Something must survive.
如果我死了
If not me,
至少让我的话留传下去
then my words at least.
走吧  快走
Go. Go.
我打了一场漂亮的仗
I fought a good fight.
我完成了使命
I finished the race.
我信主不曾动摇
And I kept the faith.
保禄被罗马人斩首
Paul is beheaded by the Romans,
但他的话世代留传
but his words live on.
他的书信构成了《新约》中近一半的内容
His letters form nearly half of the New Testament.
但终结篇章尚未完成
But the final chapter is yet to be written.
罗马人没能毒死若望
The Romans fail to kill John.
在挫败中  他们把他流放
In frustration, they exile him
到希腊
to a penal colony in Greece.
一个名叫帕特摩的海岛
An island called Patmos.
若望在这里度过了余生
Here, John lives out his days...
写下了《默示录》
and writes Revelation,
《圣经》的最后一卷
the last book of the Bible.
如今人们
The people today-
称你为王
they called you king.
他们认为你是默西亚
They think you are the Messiah.
但你们说我是谁呢
Who do you think I am?
你是天主的儿子
You are the Son of God.
倘若他不是默西亚呢
What if he's not the one?
我们以生命冒险  是为了什么
We're risking our lives. For what?
他已经向我们展示了他的能力
He has shown us his power.
我们要相信他
We must have faith in him.
不要怕
Don't be afraid.
要相信天主
Trust in God.
也要相信我
Trust in me also.
我要去的地方  你们认得那条路
You know the way to where I'm going.
我们都不知道你往哪里去
We don't know where you're going.
怎么会认得那条路呢
How can we know the way?
我是道路
I am the way,
真理
the truth...
和生命
and the life.
我是阿耳法
I am the Alpha...
我是敖默加
and the Omega.
最初的
The First...
和最末的
and the Last.
是元始
The Beginning...
也是终末
and the End.
主啊
My Lord.
我一直在等待死亡的降临
I had been expecting death to come.
以后再也没有死亡
There will be no more death...
再也没有悲伤  哭号
or mourning or crying...
和苦楚
or pain.
因为先前的都已过去了
I am making everything new.
是的
Yes.
我必快来
I am coming soon.
愿上主的恩宠
May the grace of the Lord...
常与天主的子民同在
be with all God's people.
阿们
Amen.
如果你想为天主教的影视字幕出一份福传的力量， 请来Q群180574695【天主的译站】指导交流!